<resources>


    <string name="zangi_name">Architectural Complex Zengi-Ata(14-20c.)</string>
    <string name="zangi_address">M-34,Zangioat district, Tashkent</string>
    <string name="zangi_tel">(91)967-72-58</string>
    <string name="zangi_web">no website</string>
    <string name="zangi_desciripyion">The Zengi-Ata architectural complex is located in the Zengi-Ata settlement near Tashkent. This monument represents a huge historical and art value. The ensemble has been built on the location of the burial place of sheikh Aj-Hodzha, nicknamed Zengi-Ata, which means "black", living from the end of 12th to first half of 13th century. He was the fifth murid of Sufi Hodzha Ahmad Jassavi, who was considered the spiritual head of all the Turkic tribes of Central Asia and Kazakhstan, and the pupil of mystic poet Suleyman Khaki - aka Bakyrgani. As the legend says, the beginning of the construction of this ensemble was initiated by Amir Timur. He also constructed the mausoleums of the famous saint Zengi-ata and his wife Ambar-bibi.

\n\nThe ensemble consists of three territories: an extensive garden, a complex constructed in the 14-19 c. - the mosque, medressa, minaret and the mausoleum of Ambar-bibi. The entrance to the ensemble is accessed through Darvazakhana. It is presented as a portal-dome construction with turrets - (guldasta) on the corners. Darvaza is not large: 6x7m in its lay-out, the premise inside is blocked by an arch "balkhi", the height of the building is 3.3 m., the chord of the portal arch is 4.16 m. and its height is 6.58 m. From the gate up to the entrance in the second court yard runs a path 22 m. length, alongside the Darvazakhana - the entrance to the main complex.

\n\nTo the south of the path there is a big hauz. In the southwest part of a mosque of Namazgokh type is located. The portal to the Zengi-ata mausoleum leads to the southern corner of the courtyard, the building of which is on the territory of the cemetery. The perimeter of the court yard is laden with khudjra.

\n\nTwo entrances lead to the courtyard and they are formed as portal-dome premises darvaza-khana. In 1914-15, the original minaret-tower was erected in front of the mosque. The old cemetery adjoins the historical complex from the south. From the southern entrance there is a green path that leads to the mausoleum of Ambar-bibi.</string>

    <string name="dubai_name">Dubai Restaurant</string>
    <string name="dubai_addreess">Zargarlik street, Chilanzar district</string>
    <string name="dubai_tel">(99)800-38-00</string>
    <string name="dubai_web">http://dubai.uz</string>
    <string name="dubai_desciripyion">DUBAI Restaurant is a two-story restaurant with a spacious courtyard, the design and interior of which is reminiscent of a royal palace in the East. Here you can spend your time meaningfully with your family and loved ones, relax with your friends and capture your happy moments in photos with the beautiful freshness of the restaurant for a lifetime
        \n\nDelicious dishes prepared by skilled chefs here will surely delight you as well. The menu includes Uzbek national dishes as well as European dishes.

\n\nA real restaurant should be able to not only serve delicious food to its customers, but also create an atmosphere that will delight the eyes of guests and make a pleasant impression.

</string>

    <string name="abdulkasim_name">Madrasah of Abdulkasim Sheikh</string>
    <string name="abdulkasim_address">Zargarlik street, Chilanzar district</string>
    <string name="abdulkasim_tel">no phone</string>
    <string name="abdulkasim_web">no website</string>
    <string name="abdulkasim_desciripyion">The Madrasah of Abdulkasim Sheikh, built up in 16th century, initially was a complex, which comprised mosque, bathhouse and madrasah. The place, where the complex is located, formerly called Yangi Mahalla, was one of the public centers.
        \n\nOriginally the Abdulkasim Sheikh Madrassah was a single-storey building. In 1864 when it was rebuilt a second storey was made. The Madrasah has its well-shaped portal with arch. The arcades and two towers (guldasta) at the corners flanked portal on either side. The square-shaped courtyard had a mosque, lecture rooms and is still fringed by the dormitory cells in which students lived.
        \n\nFor a long time Abdulkasim Sheikh Madrasah stood on the back street. Yet, recently it has acquired a new stately neighbor, Parliament`s building. In combination with modern, the historical building looks even more attractive. The madrasah proportions: outward: 65 x 43 m., courtyard: 28 x 22 m.
</string>

    <string name="jar_name">Jar Sport Complex stadium</string>
    <string name="jar_address">3 Beruni Avenue, Tashkent</string>
    <string name="jar_tel">(71)249-48-39</string>
    <string name="jar_web">no website</string>
    <string name="jar_desciripyion">JAR Stadium is a football stadium, located in the capital of Uzbekistan, in Tashkent. It is part of the JAR Sport Complex. The stadium seats 8,500 spectators.

\n\nJAR Stadium opened in 1998. It was renovated in 2005. At the end of 2008, when the MHSK Stadium was demolished, the Bunyodkor football club temporarily moved to the Jar Stadium, and even after building its new Bunyodkor Stadium (now Milliy Stadium) in 2013, the club held some home matches at this stadium the end of 2015. In 2012, during the renovation of the Pakhtakor Stadium, at this stadium, Pakhtakor played their home games for the floor of the season. In addition, the national, olympic, youth and women teams of Uzbekistan hold some matches at this stadium.
        \n\nFrom the season of 2016, the stadium has been rented by the club - Obod. Also at the stadium, the women`s national football teams of Uzbekistan, different in age, hold their own matches. The JAR Stadium is also one of the bases of the national team of Uzbekistan and the main training stadium for preparations for matches and camps.</string>

    <string name="kukeldash_name">Kukeldash Madrasah Tashkent</string>
    <string name="kukeldash_address">Afrosiab St., Chilanza district Tashkent</string>
    <string name="kukeldash_tel">(71)242-10-82</string>
    <string name="kukeldash_web">http://kukaldosh.uz</string>
    <string name="kukeldash_desciripyion">Kukeldash Madrasah is the largest madrasah and one of the most famous historical monuments of Tashkent. It is situated in the historical heart of the city, in the area of the Chorsu square and Registan of Tashkent. In the IX and X centuries there were Kesh gates here, one of the three city gates.

\n\nKukeldash Madrasah. Uzbekistan, TashkentThe central architectural ensemble - Registan was in every big city. The buildings included in this ensemble are of refined architecture, monumentality, original idea and an unusual finish. Registan of Tashkent is not an exception; it is enough to look closely at Kukeldash Madrasah.

\n\nKukeldash Madrasah was built in the XVI century (1570) during the reign of the Shaybanid dynasty by the vizier close to Tashkent sultans Barak-Khan and Darwish Khan. The Vizier was nicknamed "kukeltash" (‘Kukeldash’), which means "foster-brother of Khan”.
\n\nKukeldash Madrasah is one of the largest madrasah of the XVI century, preserved in Central Asia. It was built of baked bricks in a traditional style of madrasah: a large courtyard surrounded by monastic cells-khujdras, a darshana (class room) and a mosque. Facade opens an elegant entrance portal with the height of almost 20 meters (peshtak), two-floor balconies with corner towers - guldasta. The portal has residual decor - majolica and glazed bricks. On the windows of the madrasah there are special sun-protective gratings - pandjara, in its patterns an attentive visitor can see woven into the pattern names, holy to any Muslim, Allah and the Prophet Muhammad..
\n\nKukeldash Madrasah was repeatedly repaired and restored, so the current appearance of the building is very different from the original, although by size and architectural design this monument of ancient architecture is not inferior to the famous medieval madrasahs of Bukhara and Samarkand.
\n\nKukeldash Madrasah. Uzbekistan, TashkentLike any other madrasah Kukeldash Madrasah was an educational institution. However, over the centuries Kukeldash Madrasah fell to decay not once. Throughout its long history the madrasah had rough time. For example, in the XVIII century there was a caravanserai here, where merchants stayed. At this time there was a destruction of the towers crowning the madrasah - guldasta. Later, in the XIX century Kukeldash Madrasah was a fortress of the Kokand rulers.
\n\nA lot of legends are associated with Kukeldash Madrasah. For example, it is believed that for a long time, it was a place of execution - from the highest parapet of the central portal unfaithful wives and criminals were thrown in bags onto Sheyhantaur street next to Kukeldash Madrasah. Another legend tells the story of an unusual sprawling pistachio tree, which for hundreds of years was growing right on one of the domes of madrasah and was considered holy.
\n\nIn the XIX century Kukeldash Madrasah survived two earthquakes, in 1868 and 1886; the arch of entrance portal was destroyed and partially restored only in the 60s of the XX century.
\n\nIn the years of Independence Kukeldash Madrasah building was completely renovated in accordance with pictures of 80s of the XIX century. Today, it is a magnificent two-storey building - the centerpiece of architectural ensemble of Tashkent Registan. After the restoration, it was decided to return the role of spiritual institution to Kukeldash Madrasah.
\n\nFrom the corner towers of madrasah muezzins call believers to namaz, in the left part of the building there are classes for students living in khujdras, in the right part religious services are held.</string>

    <string name="humo_name">Humo Arena complex</string>
    <string name="humo_address">Afrosiab St., Chilanzar district, Tashkent</string>
    <string name="humo_tel">(71)203-66-45</string>
    <string name="humo_web">http://humoarena.com/ru</string>
    <string name="humo_desciripyion">Humo ArenaIce and Uzbekistan seem to be incompatible things. Uzbekistan is always associated with the sun or hot weather, but not with ice. But since the beginning of 2019, after the completion of the Humo arena sports and entertainment complex in Tashkent, it has become possible to attend matches, tournaments and competitions in hockey, curling, short track, and figure skating.
        \n\nSince September 2019, Humo Arena has hosted regular matches of the “Higher hockey League " championship. It was an honor and a great joy to attend one of the matches of HC Humo (Tashkent) and HC Dynamo” (SPb).\n\nThe Ice Palace impressed with its size, beauty, modern architectural solutions, and versatility. The Palace is built in the shape of the wing of the Humo bird of happiness. There is a multi-level parking lot nearby. The complex meets all modern safety and equipment requirements, accommodates 12 thousand 500 spectators.</string>

    <string name="hilton_name">Hilton Tashkent city</string>
    <string name="hilton_address">2 Islam Karimov Street, Blocks 5</string>
    <string name="hilton_tel">(71)210-88-88</string>
    <string name="hilton_web">http://hilton.com</string>
    <string name="hilton_desciripyion">Located in Tashkent, Hilton Tashkent City has a bar and a terrace. It features a restaurant, indoor pool and a rooftop Pan-Asian restaurant with city views. It offers a 24-hour front desk, room service and free Wi-Fi throughout.

\n\nAll air-conditioned rooms are equipped with a minibar, free Wi-Fi and a flat-screen TV. The private bathroom comes with a separate rain shower, bathtub, hairdryer and slippers. Free toiletries are provided.

\n\nShosh Restaurant serves a daily buffet breakfast, and Uzbek and international dishes are served for lunch. The Tumbler Bar has a terrace and serves traditional bar-style food. At the lobby lounge, guests can make use of the business center or meet over a cup of tea or coffee. City 21 Pan Asian Hotel - Restaurant is located on the 22nd floor of the highest part of the city. There is a seasonal outdoor terrace, a lounge bar and a separate room for family or business dining. The menu includes Southeast Asian cuisine, creative cocktails and spirits.

\n\nThe Hilton Tashkent City has a fitness center and 24-hour room service. The spa and wellness center offers beauty treatments, massages and steam saunas. The hotel has meeting rooms. The Executive Lounge offers free drinks and snacks throughout the day.

\n\nThe hotel is about a 10-minute walk from Xalqlar Dostligi Metro Station. The hotel is 7 km from the airport and 5 km from the train station.

\n\nCouples in particular like the location - they rated it 9.5 for a two-person trip .

\n\nWe speak your language!</string>

    <string name="navoiy_name">A.Navoi national library of Uzbekistan</string>
    <string name="navoiy_address">Yunusabad district, street Navoi, 1</string>
    <string name="navoiy_tel">(71)232-83-92</string>
    <string name="navoiy_web">http://www.natlib.uz</string>
    <string name="navoiy_desciripyion">The library was founded in 1870 as the Tashkent Public Library. The Ministry of Public Education, the Academy of Sciences, the Public Library, the Geographical Society, and the General Staff of Russia assisted in organizing the library\'s collection by donating duplicate editions from their book depositories. By May 1870, more than 2200 volumes (1200 titles) had been collected, which formed the book core of the future library.

\n\nIts manuscript fund by 1917 was 250 volumes. During this period the first lithographic books published in the lithographs of Khiva and Tashkent were also purchased. These are lithographs of "Hamsa" by A. Navoi (1880), "Diwani Munis", "Diwani Raji", the work of the famous poet of the XVIII century Sufi Allayar "Stability of the weak" and many others.

\n\nIn 1920, the library was given the status of a "state" library. From this year on the library began to receive obligatory copies of all publications published in the territory of Turkestan region. In 1925, the library\'s collection amounted to 140,000 storage pieces.

\n\nAs a result of the separation of the Central Asian republics, the library remained subordinate to the People\'s Commissariat of Uzbekistan and provided practical assistance to the newly created Central Asian republics in the organization of librarianship.

\n\nBy a decision of the Government of Uzbekistan, the State Public Library in Tashkent was declared the Central Depository of Oriental Manuscripts of the republic in 1933.

\n\nAfter the Second World War, the main task of the library was to replenish the book collections. Books from Bulgaria, Hungary, the GDR, Poland, Romania, and Czechoslovakia began to arrive. Friendship ties with libraries of Great Britain, USA, France, Germany, Japan, etc. were established.

\n\nIn 1948, the library was named after the great Uzbek poet and thinker Alisher Navoi and opened a new three-story building with reading rooms for 350 seats. At the same time, the department of rare and ancient publications was organized, where 2 thousand books were collected, including 250 with autographs, 151 - with ex libris. Now this fund counts more than 16 thousand copies.
\n\nPresidential Decree of 2 February 2019 on the establishment of the Agency of Information and Mass Communications under the Administration of the President has been designated as the authorized body to support the library\'s information activities. In this regard, the National Library of Uzbekistan was assigned new tasks.
</string>


    <string name="app_name">Travelling app course</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Android Studio</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="menu_gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="menu_slideshow">Slideshow</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="uzbekistan_samarkand_registan_square">Uzbekistan, Samarkand , Registan </string>
    <string name="infod">Registon (fors. — mayda tosh toʻshalgan joy) — Oʻrta Sharq mamlakatlari shaharlaridagi markaziy maydon, Turli maqsadlarda odamlar toʻplanadigan joy boʻlgan R. koʻp hollarda shahar arki yoki hokimlar saroylari yoni (Buxoro, Shahrisabz, Xiva)da barpo etilgan hamda ular maʼmuriy siyosiy ahamiyatga ega boʻlgan. Dastlab meʼmoriy jihatdan sodda boʻlgan; koʻpchilik tomonidan toptaladigan bu joyga yozda tuprogʻi oʻynab ketishi, yogʻingarchilik paytida botqoqlikka aylanishidan saqlash maqsadida qumtoshlar yotqizilgan. Shu xususiyati bilan boshqa ochiqjoylardan farqlangan. Keyinchalik davrlar oʻtishi bilan R. atrofiga mahobatli jamoat binolari (jome masjidi, Madrasa, devon kabilar) qurilgan, hovuz, daraxtlar bilan obodonlashtirilib, hashamatli koʻrinish olgan. Mas, Buxoro R.i arkning jan.da joylashgan. 10-asrda bu maydonni Somoniylar saroyi, devonxonalar qurshab olgan.</string>
    <string name="navigate">Navigate</string>
    <string name="samarkand_registan_square">Samarkand Registan square</string>
</resources>